(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
6/17 Birthday!!
おはようございまーす、皆さん！
Good morning, everyone!
世界のどこかでは、きっと今も朝。
Somewhere in the world, it must be morning even now.
あさココLIVEの時間がやってまいりました！
The time for Asacoco Live has arrived!
まだ寝ている人は...
For those who are still sleeping...
起きて起きて起きて！起きてくださいね。
Wake up, wake up, wake up! Please wake up.
今日も様々なニュースが入っているということで、
Since we have various news today as well,
早速見ていきましょう！
let's dive right in!
それでは、移動させていただきまして...
Now then, let me move over...
早速ですが、私の頭の上でこちら...
Right away, right above my head here...
ガタガタと騒ぎ始めているのは、
making all this noise,
視聴者コメンテーターの皆さんです。おはようございます！
are the viewer commentators. Good morning!
あ、おめでたいことを言っている奴らがいますね。
Ah, I see some people saying congratulatory things.
本日も盛り上がっていきましょう！早速ニュースです。
Let's get hyped today as well! First, the news.
速報です。
Breaking news.
桐生Cコ氏、理由明かされぬまま卒業へ。
Kiryu C-ko to graduate without the reason being revealed.
先日行われました配信により、
In a recent stream,
桐生Cコ氏がホロライブを...
it was revealed that Kiryu C-ko...
...卒業してしまうことが判明いたしました。
...will be graduating from Hololive.
こちらの卒業が発表されたことにより、
With the announcement of this graduation,
ファンの皆さんの間では...
among the fans...
「ついに逮捕か」
"Finally being arrested?"
「何年務めるんですか？」
"How many years will you serve?"
「ピー、ピー、ピー、ピー、ピー...」
[Bleep, bleep, bleep, bleep, bleep...]
「保釈金が必要ならスパチャします」
"If you need bail money, I'll Super Chat you."
これは非常に、様々な憶測が回っているようですね。
It seems many different speculations are circulating.
いやちょっと、もう画面に見せられないようなことまで
Gosh, there are even things I can't show on screen
いろいろと書かれているようですが...
being written, but...
いや、逮捕されるわけねーだろ！
Hey, there's no way I'm being arrested!
「何年」...務めねーよ、ボケ！
"How many years"... I'm not serving time, you idiot!
「保釈金が必要ならスパチャします」...務めねーわ！
"If you need bail money, I'll Super Chat you"... I'm not serving time!
捕まってねー、拘留されねーよ！
I'm not caught, I'm not being detained!
というわけでね、あの、ちょっとあの...
Anyway, uh, let's just...
ハロー、朝のこのみなさんだったらね、あの、やはり
Hello, for all you early birds, I'm sure you
何か危ないことをしていたのではないかという噂が立っているようですが…
heard rumors that I've been up to something dangerous...
これはね、ちょっとあの…
Wait, what's with this...
「何年務めるんですか？」「長けりゃあるか！」
"How many years are you serving?" "The longer the better!" No way!
と、わけだね、あの、まあ、あの…
So, anyway...
「草」「草」「草じゃないんだよバカヤロウ！」
"Lol" "Lol"... It's not funny, you idiots!
まあ、ちょっとね、あの世間をお騒がせしているC子氏なようですが、
Well, it seems Ms. C-ko is causing quite a stir,
この卒業という件のせいか…
perhaps because of this whole graduation thing...
なんと！以前発売され大人気でありました「桐生会」代紋、
Incredibly! The Kiryu-kai emblem, which was incredibly popular,
こちらのグッズがフリマサイトで超高騰しているということなんですね。
is now selling for astronomical prices on flea market sites.
お値段が、1万5500円！2万円！
Prices like 15,500 yen! 20,000 yen!
おいおいおいおい、高すぎますねこれは。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, this is way too expensive.
代紋がですね、このように転売されているということがあるようですね。
It seems the emblems are being resold like this.
これに対して有識者は…
Regarding this, an expert says...
元値は1500円、再販の可能性もあるので、
The original price was 1,500 yen, and there's a possibility of a resale,
この値段以上では買わない方がいいということですね。
so you shouldn't buy them for more than that.
いや皆さんこれ、元々1500円ですからね、代紋。
Everyone, these were originally 1,500 yen. The emblems.
1500円ですよ。
They were only 1,500 yen.
10倍以上で売られているのはちょっといかがなものなのでしょうか。
Is it really okay for them to be sold at over ten times the price?
皆さん転売はノー、転売はノーですね。
Reselling is a No, everyone. No to reselling.
気をつけていただきたいと思います。
Please be careful out there.
再販される可能性もありますからね。あの、待っていた方がいいですね。
There's a chance they'll be resold. It's better to wait.
買い損ねた皆さんも、転売屋からは買わないようにお願いします。
For those who missed out, please don't buy from resellers.
それでは次です。
Now for the next story.
なんと、悲報が入ってきているようですね。こちらです。
It seems we've received some sad news. Here it is.
桐生C子氏、まあ卒業してしまうということで、
Ms. Kiryu C-ko is graduating,
ファンの方から「卒業後も声が聞きたい」という声があったようで。
and fans have expressed that they "want to hear her voice even after graduation."
そのような声に応えるために、C子氏、
To respond to those voices, Ms. C-ko
音声の素材をメン限で配布したようなのですね。
apparently distributed voice materials to members.
「桐生ココロイド作成用音声素材」
"Voice Materials for Creating Kiryu Coco-roid"
Free voice materials for memes and Coco-roid と書いてありますが。
It says "Free voice materials for memes and Coco-roid."
内容はですね、ひらがなをね、50音、
The content is just her saying the 50 hiragana sounds,
あ、い、う…とか言ってるだけ。
like "a, i, u..."
あとまあ数字をね、1、2…って言ってるだけの。
And also just saying numbers, like "1, 2..."
誰が得するのかわからないようなね、まあ一応要望はあったんですけどね、声が聞きたいっていう。
It's hard to say who benefits from this, but there were requests from people saying they want to hear her voice.
まあこれではないのかもしれませんが、
Well, maybe this isn't exactly what they wanted,
配布してしまったようなんですね。ところが、まあ悲報ですからね、一体何があったのでしょうか。
but she distributed them. However, since it's "sad news", what on earth happened?
なんと！「濁点がない」とファンの方から不満が続出してしまったようなんですね。
Unbelievably! Fans are complaining that "there are no voiced sounds"!
だ、濁点？いや、これは忘れていたのでしょうか。
V-voiced sounds? Oh, did she forget those?
確かに「あいうえお」だけでは
Indeed, it seems you can't complete
桐生ココロイドは完成はしなそうですね。他にも…
the Kiryu Coco-roid with just that. In addition...
「ガンギマリ」も言えない世の中なんて。
A world where you can't even say "gangimari"...
「ガチ恋」を言わせないのは、させる気がないからでは？
Not letting us say "gachikoi"... is it because you don't want us to fall for you?
まあ確かにガチ恋も今言えないですね、あのままでは。
Well, it's true you can't say "gachikoi" right now, the way it is.
「M○キーマウス」が言えない。
"M*ickey Mouse" can't be said.
いや、M○キーマウスは普通に言えるだろ。普通に今の素材で言えるだろバカヤロウ。てか何を言わせてんだよ。
Wait, you can say M*ickey Mouse normally. You can say it with the current materials, you idiot. Also, what are you trying to make me say?
「H ASMRまだですか？」などと言う不満が…
"Where is the H ASMR?" Such complaints...
いや、H ASMR関係なくない？
Wait, doesn't H ASMR have nothing to do with it?
っていう不満が続出してしまったらしいんですね。濁点を忘れてしまったばかりに。
Anyway, it seems complaints flooded in just because she forgot the voiced sounds.
というわけで、本日、桐生C子氏、
So, today, Ms. Kiryu C-ko
濁音・半濁音、が、とか、ぱ、とかですね、こちらを急遽録音し追加したと。
hurriedly recorded and added voiced and semi-voiced sounds like "ga" and "pa".
そうですねぇ...
Indeed...
有識者C氏によると...
According to Expert C...
「これで満足か」などと勝ち誇っているようですが...
He seems to be gloating, saying "Is this enough?" and such, but...
皆さんの意見は...
What are all your opinions?
えー、草。
Um, "kusa" (LOL).
草を生やしているようですね。
It seems everyone is spamming "kusa".
まあこれでね、桐生ココロイドが完成すれば、
Well, if the Kiryu Cocoroid is completed through this,
卒業した後も好きに、桐生ココの声を、
even after graduation, you'll be able to hear Kiryu Coco's voice
あなたの聞きたい言葉をしゃべってくれるということでね、
saying whatever words you want to hear.
非常に便利そうですね。
That seems extremely convenient.
えー、桐生ココロイドの完成を待ちたいと思います。
I'd like to wait for the completion of the Kiryu Cocoroid.
それでは次です。
Now, on to the next one.
クソ
Crap
あ、クソですね。
Ah, it's "kuso" (crap).
クソみたいな速報が入っているようです。
It seems some crappy breaking news has come in.
えー、クソザコでも、クソダサでもなく、ただのクソ。
Not "shitty weakling" or "shitty uncool", just plain "shit".
一体どういうことなのでしょうか。
What could this possibly mean?
なんと、先日配信されましたこちらの「バカタレドラゴンズ」、
Surprisingly, in this "Bakatare Dragons" streamed the other day,
こちらのバカタレドラゴンズから生まれました罰ゲームが、
the punishment game born from this Bakatare Dragons
桐生ココ氏の中で流行しているようですね。
seems to be a hot topic for Kiryu Coco.
一体どのような罰ゲームかと言いますと、
As for what kind of punishment game it is,
なんと！
Unbelievably!
負けた人が7月1日、
the loser, until July 1st,
つまり桐生ココ氏の卒業する日まで、
which is the day of Kiryu Coco's graduation,
配信画面のどこかに、うんこをね、なんと置かなければ、
must place a poop emoji somewhere on their stream screen,
置き続けなければいけないという、あまりにも重い罰ゲーム。
and keep it there. An incredibly heavy punishment.
こちらがね、えー、ちょっとはまっちゃってるみたいですねぇ。
This seems to have become a bit of a craze.
いやー、これは汚いですねぇ。
Wow, this is dirty.
アイドルとして負けたら終わりになりそうですが、
It seems like it'd be the end for an idol if they lost, but...
この配信でなんと負けてしまったのは、F氏。
the one who unfortunately lost this stream was F-shi.
そしてね、いや、F氏、負けちゃったみたいでこれ、
And well, it looks like F-shi lost, so check this out.
よく見てください。配信画面の右側に、
Look closely. On the right side of the stream screen,
ああ！ありますね、うんこが！
Ah! There it is, a poop!
うわ、これは、これはアイドルとしては非常に致命的には見えますが、
Whoa, this looks quite fatal for an idol, but...
これね、しかもね、なんと、2回目があったんですよ。
there was actually a second time for this.
一人の犠牲者を出してしまったこのうんこ罰ゲーム。
This poop punishment game that already claimed one victim.
6月14日、えー、このメンバーで行われたマリパ。
On June 14th, in the Mario Party stream with these members,
こちらでですね、また犠牲者が出てしまったようですねぇ。
it seems another victim has appeared.
ああーっ！あら、これ、モザイク。
Ahhh! Oh, this, a mosaic.
あら、モザイク班がちょっとモザイク忘れちゃってますが、
Oh, the mosaic team seems to have forgotten the mosaic, but...
敗者となってしまった毛玉氏。
the loser was Kedama-shi.
こちら配信画面のどこかに、どこかにあるようですね、うんこが。
It seems there's a poop somewhere on this stream screen.
探してみましょう。
Let's look for it.
あ、これ。
Ah, this.
うわっ！またしても、またしても、犠牲者が出てしまっていますねぇ。
Whoa! Once again, yet another victim has appeared.
頭の上にね、とぐろ巻いてますね、これ。
It's coiled right on top of her head.
これは、アイドルとしてはやっぱね、さすがに、
As an idol, well, naturally...
まあ罰ゲームをしっかり守ってくださってるというのは素晴らしい心意気の毛玉だとは思いますが、
I think it's a wonderful spirit for Kedama to strictly follow the punishment game, but...
おね、あのうんこがね、2箇所、確認できました。
well, I've confirmed two instances of that poop.
いやー、この罰ゲームね、非常にね、やられた側はたまらないですけれどもねぇ。
Wow, this punishment game is truly unbearable for those on the receiving end.
しかも、こちらの毛玉、なんと、この罰ゲーム、えー、決定してしまった瞬間、
Furthermore, this Kedama, surprisingly, at the moment this punishment was decided,
つまり負けの瞬間に、なんと93.1万人、
meaning the moment of her loss, reached 931,000 subscribers.
クサイ万人を達成していたというのですから、
Since she reached "kusai" (stinky) thousand,
これはね、いや、約束された負けなのではないかと話題になっているようですね。
it's becoming a hot topic that this might have been a destined defeat.
これに対し有識者C氏は、
Regarding this, Expert C says,
えー、今後の対戦コラボにも期待したいということですね。
that they want to look forward to future battle collaborations.
おっと、左側に、また犠牲者が出そうな対戦の予定があるようですね。
Oops, on the left, there seems to be a scheduled battle where another victim might appear.
皆さん、楽しみですねぇ。それでは、ここで、
Everyone, look forward to it. Now, at this point...
CMです。
A commercial.
あ〜 暑い、でも寒い...
Ah~ It's hot, but cold...
おっ、なんだか辛そうですね。
Oh, you look like you're having a hard time.
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
ココちー、最近一気に暑くなってきて汗が出てきちゃって。
Coco-chi, it's suddenly gotten hot lately and I'm starting to sweat.
でもクーラーを付けたら一気に部屋が寒くなるし...
But if I turn on the AC, the room suddenly gets cold...
今はちょうど温度の調節が難しい季節な気がしますね。
I feel like it's exactly the season where it's hard to adjust the temperature.
そうなんだよー。
That's right~.
今は体調管理も大切だから
Now health management is important too,
安易に体を冷やしちゃいけないしねえ。
so we shouldn't let our bodies get cold too easily.
困ったなあ...
I'm in a bind...
この服は暑すぎるし
This outfit is too hot,
この服じゃ寒いかな。
and this one might be too cold.
なるほど、今の季節にぴったりの服を選ぶのは
I see, choosing the perfect outfit for this season
大変そうですねえ。
seems quite difficult, doesn't it?
ああ、こんな時に暑さも寒さも
Ah, if only there were an outfit
気軽に調節できる服があればなあ。
that could easily adjust for both heat and cold.
その言葉を、待っていたんです！
Those were the words I was waiting for!
え、まさか？
Eh, no way?
そのまさかです。あのあさココブランドが
That very way. That Asacoco brand
ついにアパレル業界に参入。
is finally entering the apparel industry!
この季節にぴったりのあれが
That certain item perfect for this season
ついに発売開始。
is finally on sale.
あのCコさんも愛用中。
That C-ko-san is also a fan.
その名も、代紋ジャージ！
Its name is, the Crest Jersey!
やった！待ってました！
Yay! I've been waiting for this!
このジャージなら着脱簡単。
Putting it on and taking it off is easy.
寒い時はしっかり肩まで着用、
Wear it up to your shoulders when it's cold,
暑い時はゆるく腕まで。
and loosely down to your arms when it's hot.
それだけじゃないんです。
And that's not all.
激しいバイオレンスな気持ちが
When you can't suppress those
抑えられない時は、
intense, violent feelings,
袖を引きちぎって世紀末スタイルに！
tear off the sleeves for a post-apocalyptic style!
おお、暑さにも寒さにも
Oh, this jersey that handles heat, cold,
世紀末にも対応しているこのジャージ。
and even the end of the world.
使い勝手は圧倒的ですけど、
Its utility is overwhelming, but
もしかして結構高い？
could it be quite expensive?
袖引きちぎっちゃったけど。
I already tore off the sleeves, though.
そんなことはないんです。
That's not the case at all.
なんとこちらのジャージ、
Believe it or not, this jersey,
桐生ココ誕生日記念ということで、
to celebrate Kiryu Coco's birthday,
一万円にて販売開始！
is going on sale for 10,000 yen!
い、一万円！？
T-Ten thousand yen!?
紙きれ一枚で買えるなんてお得すぎる！
It's too much of a bargain! I only need one bill!
今すぐ注文しなきゃ！
I've got to order it right now!
超お得な代紋ジャージ。
The super bargain Crest Jersey.
ホロライブの代紋も入っていて超可愛い。
It even has the Hololive crest and it's super cute.
販売期間は短くなっておりますので、
The sales period is limited,
皆様忘れずにご購入を。
so everyone, don't forget to get yours.
というわけで皆様！
And so, everyone!
待望のこちら、販売決定いたしました！
The sale of this long-awaited item has been decided!
いや、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you. Thank you very much.
こちらですね、桐生Cコ氏も愛用しております。
This right here, Kiryu C-ko also uses it.
このジャージ、販売です、ついに。
This jersey is finally on sale.
着るタイプが出てしまいましたね。
The wearable type is finally out.
こちらね、実際にスタッフさんに着用してもらった
Here are some images of our staff members
画像を送っていただきました。あさココ用にですね。
actually wearing it. They were sent for Asacoco.
このような形でね、着るとね、なります。
This is what it looks like when you put it on.
注目すべきはこの真ん中の画像ですね。
Please note the middle image here.
チャックの部分を上の方まで完全に上げていただきますと、
If you pull the zipper all the way up to the top,
帽子の方までね、完全に覆うことができます。
it can completely cover your face up to the hood.
これはこのご時世のことも考えられているのでしょうか。
I wonder if it was designed for current times.
さらにかっこいいポイントがありまして、こちら！
There's an even cooler feature, look at this!
内側にね、このようにタグが付いてるんですけど、
There's a tag on the inside like this,
このタグにかっこいい代紋がね、
and on this tag, a cool crest is
しっかりプリントされてるんですね。
clearly printed.
これは皆様、いや本当にね、かっこいいんでね、
Everyone, no really, it's so cool,
全てにおいて手に入れるしかないのではないでしょうか。
you'll just have to get one for yourself.
そして、パーカーの話ばかりしてしまいましたが、こちら。
And while I've been talking only about the hoodie, look at this.
四期生五人の集合アクリルパネルも、
An acrylic panel of all five 4th generation members
同時に誕生日記念として発売されるようなので。
will also be released for the birthday.
皆様、こちらは三千円となっております。
Everyone, this one is 3,000 yen.
販売開始の時間は九時、九時となっておりますね。
The sales start at 9:00, yes, 9:00.
この配信が終わった時間ですね。
That's right after this stream ends.
皆様、ホロライブのグッズ、チェックしてみてくださいね。
Everyone, please check out the Hololive goods.
ぜひ、こちら、もう手に入れとかないと損するのでないでしょうか。
By all means, you'll be missing out if you don't get this.
早速ですね、あの買っちゃってる人がいるんですけど、
Already, there are some people who have bought it,
まあ、着るタイプとね。スパチャでは買えないことだけ注意してください。
but just be aware you can't buy the wearable type with Super Chats.
あの、分かって頂ければと思います。
Well, I hope you understand.
まだ販売してないですからね！
They're not for sale yet!
おっ、なんとこれ！
Oh? What's this?
なんと、超速報が入ってしまいました！
Breaking news has just come in!
再販決定！
Resale confirmed!
決定です、皆さん、なんと！
It's confirmed, everyone! Check this out!
本日より再販決定！！
Starting today, a resale has been confirmed!!
こちら！これまで販売されまして、
This! The items that have been on sale before...
超大人気でした、桐生会大紋、
...and were incredibly popular: the Kiryu-kai Crest,
ハメルタイプのあさココ、桐生会マフティースマホケース、
the Plug-type Asacoco, and the Kiryu-kai smartphone case...
すべて本日9時より再販が決定いたしました！
...they will all be available for resale starting at 9 PM tonight!
これです、皆さん！
This is it, everyone!
あの、今頃ね、フリマサイトで出してた人は、
Those of you who were selling them on flea market sites...
「おい！」って思ってるかもしれませんが、
...might be thinking, "Oh no!"
こちらの大紋、1500円でまた販売させて頂きますので、
But these will be sold again for 1,500 yen!
1500円、1500円ですからね！
1,500 yen! 1,500 yen!
皆さんこちらを買って頂いたほうが、断然お得ですからね！
So you're much better off buying them from here, everyone!
ファンの皆さんが再販してほしいと言って頂きましたので、
Many fans asked for a resale...
その声が叶いました！
...and your voices have been heard!
皆さんぜひね、この機会を逃さないようにお願いいたします。
Everyone, please don't miss this opportunity!
あれ？なんか今日、今日の配信、何でしたっけ？
Wait... what was today's stream about again?
なんか大事なことを忘れている気が...
I feel like I'm forgetting something important...
うーん、まあ、まあいいか！とりあえず次のニュースです。
Well, whatever. Anyway, on to the next news.
あっ、大ニュースです！なんと！
Oh! Big news!
桐生ココ、黒田崇矢氏からエール
A shoutout for Kiryu Coco from Takaya Kuroda
桐生ココ、黒田崇矢氏からエール。黒田崇矢、
Yes, Takaya Kuroda...
桐生一馬の声優さんとして非常に有名な大々大有名人の方から、
...the world-famous voice actor of Kazuma Kiryu...
なんとね、エールを直接頂いちゃっていたことが分かりました。
...has sent a direct shoutout!
いや、これはちょっと嬉しすぎますね！
Wow, I'm just too happy about this!
卒業ライブ頑張ってくださいということですから、
He said, "Good luck with your graduation live!"
これはね、もう頑張るしかないですね！
So I really have no choice but to do my best!
そしてですね、次のニュースです。
And now, the next news.
おっ、たつのこの方から情報が入りましたね。
Oh? We have some interesting information from a Tatsunoko.
会長、どこかのドラゴンのお誕生日をお祝いする競馬レースが、
Chairman, it seems a horse race to celebrate...
開催されるようです。
...'a certain dragon's' birthday is being held.
一体どういうことなのか、こちら調べてみましたところ、なんと！
What on earth could this mean? We looked into it and...
ゲポカワドラゴン生誕記念！？
The "Gepokawa Dragon Birthday Commemoration"?
金沢競馬場、誕生日くらいガチ恋しなさい。
At the Kanazawa Racecourse? "Love me as much as your birthday"?
先日このような競馬レースが、たつのこの皆さんの共産により、
It seems such a horse race was held recently...
行われてしまったようですね。
...sponsored by all you Tatsunoko fans!
えっ、ってことは...
Wait, that means...
あのニュースを忘れていました！なんと本日！
I forgot *that* news!
本日桐生ココ3501歳の誕生日！！
Today is Kiryu Coco's 3,501st birthday!!
本日桐生ココ3501歳の誕生日を迎えてしまったようですね。
Today is Kiryu Coco's 3,501st birthday!
誕生日のお知らせがグッズより遅く来たのは、
Wait, the birthday announcement came later than the goods announcement?
誕生日配信ではこれが初めてなんじゃないの？
Isn't this the first time for a birthday stream?
というわけで皆さん、お誕生日配信お楽しみください。
So everyone, please enjoy the birthday stream!
これから始まるみたいですよ！
It seems it's about to begin!
いやあ...
Man...
なんか、あさココ久しぶりに見ちゃいましたけど、
It's been a while since I watched Asacoco...
なんかあれ、あの、最後のニュースあれ、あれちょっと気づいちゃいました。
But that last news... I just realized something.
あれ間違ってない！？
Wasn't that wrong?!
3501歳の誕生日迎えてねえんだよ。
I'm not having my 3,501st birthday!
3502歳だよ！
I'm 3,502 years old!
いやあ、皆さんのコメントでね、あの気づいちゃいましたねこれ。
Man, I noticed it because of everyone's comments.
おいおいおい、なんで気づか...
Hey, hey, hey! Why didn't anyone notice?
ああこれ、こんなのダメだよ、せっかくの誕生日配信なのに。
This is terrible... and it's my birthday stream, too.
こんなのって、ダメだね。
How could this happen...
ダメだね...
It's so pathetic...
だめよ...
Dame yo...
だめなのよ...
It's no good...
ばかみたい。
Like a fool.
馬鹿みたい 子供なのね
I'm such a fool... just a child.
夢を追って傷ついて
Chasing dreams and getting hurt.
嘘が下手なくせに
Even though I'm terrible at lying,
笑えない笑顔見せた
I showed you a smile I couldn't mean.
I love youも ろくに言わない
I couldn't even say "I love you" properly.
口下手でほんまに不器用
So awkward and truly clumsy with words.
なのになのにどうして
But why, oh why?
サヨナラは言えたの
Why could I say goodbye?
だめだね だめよ だめなのよ
It's no good... no good... it's just no good.
あんたが好きで好きすぎて
I love you, I love you too much.
どれだけ強いお酒でも
No matter how strong the drink,
歪まない思い出が 馬鹿みたい
My memories won't fade... I'm such a fool.
馬鹿みたい ほんとバカね
I'm such a fool... a real idiot.
あんた信じるばかりで
Just for believing in you.
強い女のふり
Pretending to be a strong woman,
切なさの夜風浴びる
I'm bathed in the painful night breeze.
一人になって 3年が過ぎ
Three years have passed since I became alone,
街並みさえも変わりました
Even the city streets have changed.
なのになのにどうして
But why, oh why?
未練だけ置き去り
Leaving only lingering regrets behind.
ほんまに ろくな男やない
You're truly no good at all.
揃いの指輪はずします
I'm taking off our matching ring.
ざまあみろ せいせいするわ
Serves you right... I feel refreshed.
いい加減 待ってても 馬鹿みたい
Waiting forever... I'm such a fool.
だめだね だめよ だめなのよ
It's no good... no good... it's just no good.
あんたが好きで好きすぎて
I love you, I love you too much.
どれだけ強いお酒でも
No matter how strong the drink,
歪まない思い出が 馬鹿みたい
My memories won't fade... I'm such a fool.
ざまあみろ せいせいするわ
Serves you right... I feel refreshed.
なんなのよ この涙
What are these tears?
馬鹿みたい
I'm such a fool.
やー！馬鹿みたいな間違いしちゃいました！
Aah! I made such a stupid mistake!
思わず笑っちゃいましたよ、そして。ついでに歌ってみました。
I couldn't help but laugh! And so, I ended up singing it too.
間違えましたよ、もう！
I made a mistake, geez!
3500、に、2歳ですから私は！
3500, and 2... I'm 3502 years old!
皆さん、今日はね、こちらの配信に遊びに来てくれて
Everyone, thank you so much for coming
本当にありがとうございます！
to play in today's stream!
桐生ココ、本日は、3502！
Kiryu Coco, today... 3502!
もう、なんで間違えちゃったんだろう。
Geez, why did I mess up?
あれ、わざとじゃなくてマジで間違えたんですけど、
That wasn't on purpose, I really messed up.
ちょっと、あの予定外ですね。
It's a bit unexpected.
だめだねー、だめだねー。
Dame da ne, dame da ne.
いやしかしね、あの、でもだめだねをね、もっとさらにね、
But you know, I was able to sing 'Dame Da Ne'
心を込めて歌うことができたので、まあいいってことにしましょう！
with even more heart, so let's just say it's fine!
今日は誕生日なので、あ、わ！
Today is my birthday, so— oh, wow!
やったー、誕生日ケーキいただいちゃいました！ありがとうございます！
Yay! I got a birthday cake! Thank you so much!
え、いいんですかこれいただいちゃって。あー可愛い！
Is it okay for me to have this? Ah, it's so cute!
皆さん、いただいちゃいましたよ。誕生日といえば
Everyone, I got it. Speaking of birthdays,
バースデーケーキ、ありがとうございます！
it's the birthday cake! Thank you so much!
食べちゃおっかな。食べちゃおっかな。
Should I eat it? Should I eat it?
まずローソク。
First, the candle.
イエーイ、I made a wish!
Yay, I made a wish!
夢をね、ちゃんと託して、今ローソクを吹き消しました。
I put my dreams into it and blew out the candle just now.
みんながね、健康でいられるようにって、
With the wish that everyone stays healthy—
たつのこのみんなが健康でいられるようにというね、願いを込めて。
that all of the Tatsunoko stay healthy.
えい！あー、モグモグモグ...
Hyah! Ah— *nom nom nom*...
んー、ドラゴンの、ドラゴンサイズの一口なんで私のは。
Nn— it's a dragon-sized bite, because it's me.
もうすぐに食べれちゃうんですけど。
I can eat it up in no time.
うりゃー！せい！ヤッホー！みんなにも一口どうぞ、どうぞ。
Hah! Sei! Yahoo! Here, everyone, have a bite.
あむあむあむ、食べちゃうけどね。
Nom nom nom... but I'm gonna eat it.
いる？いる？あ、いいね、君こんなところにいたの。はい、あげる。
Want some? Want some? Oh, nice, you were here. Here, for you.
あ、美味しかったですか。
Ah, was it delicious?
おお、このカメラいいな。
Oh, this camera is good.
てんてんてんてん、今日は誕生日なんでね、
Ten-ten-ten-ten, today is my birthday,
あの、楽しく過ごしたいと思います。
so I want to spend it having fun.
皆さん、一緒にお祝いしようぜ！イエーイ！
Everyone, let's celebrate together! Yay!
あ、ちょうど見えないようになってやがる。
Ah, it's positioned so you can't see.
あ、怒られちゃうまた。くそ。
Ah, I'll get scolded again. Damn.
えい！あら、ここだね、このへんかな。あ、また取れた。
Hah! Oh, here, maybe around here. Ah, I got another piece.
これすごい美味しそうなんだよ、見て。
This looks so delicious, look.
そしてね、あーん。
And then, say ahh.
美味しいんだよ、実際に。
It really is delicious.
みんなには後でね、脳に直接送ってあげる。
I'll send it directly to your brains later.
うー！ひひひ、あ、変な形に取っちゃったな。
Waa! Hehehe, ah, I took it in a weird shape.
あと一きれだけ食べよ。
I'll eat just one more piece.
残りはね、明日にとっとこ。家持って帰ってかなたんと食べよ。
I'll save the rest for tomorrow. I'll take it home and eat it with Kanatan.
ありがとうございますケーキ用意していただいて。お腹いっぱいになっちゃったな。
Thank you so much for preparing the cake. I'm so full now.
まあ、あの誕生日といえばですね、皆さんこのようなものをご存じですか。
Well, speaking of birthdays, do you all know about this thing?
ピニャータ！
Pinata!
お腹いっぱいだったらね、あの運動ができるんですけど。ピニャータっていうね。
Since I'm full, I can get some exercise. It's called a pinata.
私が子供の頃はよくやってたんですけど、
I used to do it a lot when I was a kid—
あの箱にね、ダンボールとかそういうのにお菓子とかそういうのがいっぱい詰まってて。
it's a box, like cardboard, filled with lots of candy and stuff.
で、その箱はね、可愛い動物ですとかそういう形をしていて、
And that box is shaped like a cute animal or something,
それをね、バットとかでバーン！バーン！って、皆で叩いてね、
and everyone hits it with a bat— bang! bang!—
その中に詰まってるお菓子を落とした分だけもらえちゃうっていうの。知ってます？
and you get as much candy as falls out. Do you know it?
あれをやりたいなって思ってるんですけど。
I've been wanting to do that.
ピニャータ！
Pinata!
やりたい、やりたい、視聴者の皆さんと一緒にゲームしましょうよ、
I want to do it, I want to do it! Let's play a game with the viewers,
ピニャータゲーム。お願いします！
the Pinata game. Please!
あ、来た！
Ah, it's here!
毒々しい色してやがるぜ。
What a garish color.
え、今！
Whoa, now!
わ、何だお前、爆発しろ。
Whoa, what are you? Explode already!
よし、じゃあ今日はこれをね、視聴者の皆さんと一緒に、ちょっとしたゲームをね、楽しみたいと思います。
All right, today I'm going to enjoy a little game with this and all the viewers.
私は、目隠しをしちゃいますね。
I'm going to blindfold myself.
で、ちょっと特殊な目隠しをさせていただきまして、
And I'll be using a slightly special blindfold...
これ。
this.
今ね、目隠しをさせていただきました。
I've put on the blindfold now.
で、こちらの目隠しね、ちょっと特殊な目隠しで、
And this blindfold is a bit special—
これね、皆さんの...
it's everyone's...
コメントだけしか見えないんですよ。ふふふ。
I can only see comments. Hehehe.
The only thing I see right now are your comments. All your guys's comments, right now.
みんなのコメントしか見えなくてね。で、この状態で...
I can only see everyone's comments. So, in this state...
...えー、武器、武器！ふふふ。
...uh, weapon, weapon! Hehehe.
えーっと、よいしょ。
Um, let's see.
あ、ココだ。
Oh, it's here.
あ、あった、あった。あったかも、今。
Ah, there it is, there it is. I might have found it.
この斧をですね、使って...
I'm going to use this axe...
...えー、みんなにね、ピニャータの方まで誘導してほしいと思います。
...uh, I'd like everyone to guide me to the pinata.
みんなのコメントしか見えないからね。
Because I can only see your comments.
みんなのコメントしか見えないから。じゃあ行くよ、私。
Since I can only see your comments. Alright, here I go.
まずね、10回回るんで。行くよ！
First, I'm going to spin 10 times. Here I go!
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
みんな、どこ？
Where is it, everyone?
どこ？教えて！
Where? Tell me!
前？前？
Forward? Forward?
どこどこどこどこ？下？下？
Where where where where? Down? Down?
右、右！
Right, right!
どこ？
Where?
な、何よ！
Wh-What?!
どこどこどこ。ここ？ここやで。どこだよ！
Where where where. Here? It's here. Where is it?!
あ、どこどこどこ？
Ah, where where where?
Left?
Left, left!
えいっ！
Yah!
I think I got a hit! Yes!
You're right here! あらした！
You're right here! Take that!
Come on!
あらした！
Take that!
おらっ！おらっ！
Hah! Hah!
どこだどこだ。
Where is it, where is it?
もうちょい前か。
A bit more forward?
この辺かな？
Around here?
おらっ！
Hah!
当たってる？
Am I hitting it?
はっ？
Huh?
えいっ！
Yah!
当たった！
I hit it!
ここだここだ。Found you!
Here it is, here it is. Found you!
あらした！
Take that!
Candy's popping out!
出てきてる？
Is it coming out?
えいっ！来たー！
Yah! Here it comes!
ひひひ。
Hehehe.
もっともっと！
More, more!
Come on!
えいっ！
Yah!
いてっ。ちょっとさ、顔にも当たっちゃうよ。
Ouch. Hey, it's hitting my face too.
えいっ！おっ？
Yah! Oh?
下がりすぎ？
Did I go down too far?
えいっ！
Yah!
うわー！
Whoa!
Did it open? 開いた？
Did it open? It's open!
開いた！やったー！
It's open! Yay!
あー、みんなのおかげで、キャンディ。やったー！
Ah, thanks to everyone, candy. Yay!
いっぱい飴だ。
So many candies.
みんなにもあげよう。飴ちゃん。
I'll give some to you all too. Candies.
こういうので拾って集めるっていうのをね、あの、ちっちゃい頃ずっとやってたんで。
I used to do this all the time when I was little, picking them up and gathering them.
えー、久しぶりに、3000年ぶりくらいにできて嬉しいなー！
Eh, I'm so happy I could do it again after 3000 years!
みんな、たくさんのキャンディ。
Everyone, lots of candy.
はい、ちょっとだけ分けてあげるから。この辺、床に落ちたやつを食いな。
Here, I'll share a little bit. Eat the ones that fell on the floor here.
はいどうぞ！はい！
Here you go! Here!
可愛い。お腹が開いちゃいました。
Cute. Its belly opened up.
真っ二つや。
It's in two pieces.
可愛らしい。
Adorable.
これね、いろんなのあるんですよ、皆さん。知ってました？
You know, there are various kinds of these, everyone. Did you know?
これ、あの、こういう形が結構基本ですけど、あの、キャラクターのやつですとか...
This shape is pretty standard, but there are character ones and...
...ま、作ろうと思えば、桐生ココピニャータなんてもんも作れるんですね。
...well, if you wanted to, you could even make a Kiryu Coco pinata.
ま、そんなの、そんなのぶち叩きたくないですけどね、みんな。
Well, I wouldn't want to bash something like that, right everyone?
あー、こうね、楽しい思い出を用意してくれてありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you so much for preparing such fun memories.
ひひひ。可愛い。
Hehehe. Cute.
速報
Breaking News
あ、なんか速報入ってない？
Oh, isn't there some breaking news?
そ、そ、そ、速報？！
Br-Br-Br-Breaking news?!
※緊急VTRが入ってきました
*Urgent VTR has started
何これ？何これ何これ？
What's this? What is this, what is this?
え？緊急ブ、ブ、ブ、ブイティーアール？
Eh? Urgent V-V-V-VTR?
な、何？
Wh-What?
あ、ちょっとVTR入ったみたいで。緊急。えー、どうぞ！
Ah, looks like a VTR is starting. Urgent. Uh, here it is!
ココへ
To Coco
何これ？聞いてないんですけど！
What's this? I haven't heard about this!
えー？
Eh?
平日毎朝あさココを頑張っていたココちは、いつも一生懸命でとてもかっこ良くて、このドラゴンのためなら何でもしようと思える最強人様溢れる背中でした。
Coco-chi, who worked hard on Asacoco every weekday morning, was always so hardworking and cool. Her back, full of her powerful character, made me feel like I would do anything for this dragon.
これ聞いてないんですけど！
I haven't heard about this!
おいおい！
Hey, hey!
通販コーナーではアイドルらしくない事もいっぱいしたね！
In the home shopping segment, you did many things that weren't very idol-like!
聞いてないよ、これ！
I wasn't told about this!
お天気コーナーでは絶対天気を描かなかったから、天気付けてって毎回言いながら怒られてたっけ！それもなんだか心地よかったです！
In the weather segment, you never drew the weather, so I was always telling you to add it while getting scolded! Even that was somehow pleasant!
おおい！わため！
Hey! Watame!
デビュー後、自分がクソザコ回線な事が判明して凹んでいた時
After my debut, when I was feeling down because my internet connection was trash...
あぁー、ちょっとサプライズやめてくださいよー
Ah! Please stop with the surprises!
面白いネタに昇華してくれて、とても心が救われたことを、今までもこれからもずっと感謝してるよ。
You turned it into a funny joke, and it really saved my heart. I've been grateful ever since, and I'll continue to be forever.
わためー
Watame~
一緒にお互いのメンバースタンプを描き合おうって誘ってくれた時も、すごく嬉しかったし楽しかった。
When you invited me to draw each other's membership stamps together, I was so happy and had so much fun.
あさココの出演料として液タブをプレゼントしてくれた事もありました。わたしはまだそのお返しが出来ていません。
There was also a time you gave me a tablet as a performance fee for Asacoco. I haven't been able to return the favor yet.
懐かしいね
That brings back memories.
いつも誰がわかれ、仲間想いで、面白くて強いドラゴン
Always thoughtful of her friends, funny, and a strong dragon.
わたしもそんなドラゴンの隣に立てるぐらい強い相棒になれるよう、これからも頑張るね。これからも、わためぇ達は相棒で大事な仲間だよねぇ？
I'll keep doing my best so I can become a partner strong enough to stand by such a dragon's side. We'll always be partners and precious friends, right?
いつまでも大好きだよ、最高の相棒！
I'll love you forever, my best partner!
口に出して言うと絶対泣いちゃうから、こんな形でごめんね。
I know I'd definitely cry if I said this out loud, so I'm sorry for doing it this way.
また遊びに行こうぜ、相棒！
Let's hang out again, partner!
角巻わため
Tsunomaki Watame
おいおいおい...
Hey, hey, hey...
聞いてないよ、わため！
I wasn't told about this, Watame!
おいおいおい！なんかリハーサル短けーと思ったんだよ！
Hey, hey, hey! I thought the rehearsal felt a bit short!
なんか尺が短けーと思ったんだよ！
I thought the timing felt a bit off!
サプライズプレゼントだよ。
It's a surprise present.
びっくりした... なあ...
I was so surprised... man...
聞いてないよわため、びっくりしたよ本気で。
I didn't hear about this, Watame. I was seriously surprised.
ちょっと、何してくれとん！
Wait, what did you just do?!
プレゼントあげたいなって思ったんだけど...
I wanted to give you a present, but...
なんか物はさ、買えちゃうと思ったから...
I thought that you can just buy things, so...
思い出を形にしてプレゼントにしました。
I turned our memories into a physical form as a present.
わためー！
Watame~!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
驚かしやがって... 本当に...
Scaring me like that... Seriously...
なんだよ、こっちが泣いちゃうんだよ。
What the hell, you're gonna make me cry.
わためありがとう。
Thank you, Watame.
びっくりしたって、もう。
I was so surprised, seriously.
反応、こういうつもりじゃなかったから、ちょっと。
This wasn't the reaction I intended to have.
幸せだったよ。
I was happy.
だよね。
I thought so.
いや、マネージャーさんにお願いして、
I asked the manager,
なんかどっかで休んでもらえないでしょうかーって...
if they could have you rest somewhere for a bit...
いや、でもわため、わためはね、あさココLIVEずっと頑張ってきた、
But Watame, you've worked so hard on Asacoco LIVE,
同期でもあり、相棒だからね。
as my fellow gen-mate and partner.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
こちらこそいっぱいありがとう。
Thank you so much as well.
ちょっとあの、あの、ちょっと照明きつくしてもらっていいですか？
Um, could you turn up the lighting a bit?
鼻水映んないように。アイドルなんで、こちら。
So my runny nose doesn't show. I'm an idol, after all.
やめてもらっていいですか？やめてください！
Could you stop that? Please stop!
やめて。ローアングルやめてください、ちょっとマジで。
Stop. Please stop the low angle, seriously.
ローアングル、ローアングルやめてください。
Low angle, please stop with the low angle.
ローアングルやめてください。
Please stop the low angle.
ローアングルやめてください！
Please stop the low angle!
アピールやめてください！
Stop with the fan service!
わためありがとう。
Thank you, Watame.
あの、びっくりしたよ、本当に。
I was really surprised, honestly.
あの、こういう音楽やめろ！
Stop playing this kind of music!
まさか。ずっと助けてもらってありがとよ。
I didn't expect this. Thanks for always helping me out.
えー！助けてもらってるのは、視聴者の皆さん、こっちなんです。
Eh! The one being helped is me, and the viewers too.
わためは何でも協力してくれて、本当にありがたくて。
Watame, you've helped me with everything, I'm so grateful.
あの、もう相棒といったらわため、
When it comes to my partner, it's Watame.
私にとってはね、おめぇしかいねーんだよ。
To me, you're the only one.
嬉しいこと言うじゃねぇか。
Look at you, saying nice things.
私もおめぇしかいねぇよ。
You're the only one for me too.
あとで送るから、BGM使って。
I'll send it to you later, use the BGM.
いらねぇよ！いらねぇ、いらねぇって、
I don't need it! I told you, I don't need it.
いらねぇでしょ、これ。
I don't need this, right?
卒業したらね、あげるから。
I'll give it to you once I graduate.
いなくなっちゃうけど、あの相棒が。
Even though your partner will be gone.
ま、でも一生相棒だよな。
Well, we'll be partners for life, right?
新しい相棒なんか作んねぇよ。作んねぇよ。
I'm not gonna find a new partner. I won't.
な、卒業しても相棒だろ？
Right? We'll still be partners after graduation, right?
そうだよ！そうだよ。
That's right! That's right.
やったぜ。ちょっと駆け足になっちゃったけど。
Hell yeah. We're a bit rushed, though.
遊びに行こう。
Let's go hang out.
たくさん遊びに行こうぜ、たくさん。
Let's go out and play a lot, a lot.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
影ながらね...
From the shadows...
影、こっそり？
Shadows, secretly?
いや、こっそりしなくていいんだけど別に。うん。
No, you don't have to be secret about it. Yeah.
あの、ほら、あの、あ、あ、だ、だからあの、切るメンバーみたいにはなんないから、大丈夫。うん。
Um, look, um, so, I won't be like a member that gets cut, so it's fine. Yeah.
うん。
Yeah.
だから、あの、まあこっそり、こっそり。
So, um, well, secretly, secretly.
うん。まあこっそりじゃなくても...
Yeah. Well, even if it's not secretly...
こっそりじゃなくても、こっそりでも、仲良くしてください。
Whether it's secretly or not, please be on good terms with me.
これからも一緒にやると思ってるから、こちらこそ。
I think we'll be doing things together from now on, so same here.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
わためーな！
Watame!
Thank you!
頑張ってね！
Good luck!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうわためめめ！アイボーパーパー！
Thank you Watame-me-me! Aibo bye-bye!
バイバーイ、バイバイ、バイバイ。
Bye bye, bye bye, bye bye.
Thank you!
ちょ、本当に、本当に聞いていなかったんですけど。
Wait, really, I really didn't hear about this.
あの、流れになさすぎて、何かわかんなくて。
It was so out of the blue, I didn't know what was happening.
ちょっとこういう流れに、されちまったよー！
I got dragged into this kind of flow!
父さん皆さんどう思います？卑怯な女だよあいつは、卑怯な女だよ。
Everyone, what do you think? She's a cowardly woman, she's a cowardly woman.
こうやっていいとこ持って行きやがって！
Taking the best part for herself like that!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ああ、もちろんね、父さんの皆さんも、ずっと一緒にね、歩んできた、相棒であるということは、間違いないんですが...
Ah, of course, you everyone too, there's no doubt you are partners who have walked together for a long time, but...
わためはね、あの、ちょっと特別だったんで。
Watame was, well, a little special.
わたここてぇてぇ。
WataCoco wholesome.
次なんだっけ？
What was next?
あいた、え、ちょっとあの、ちょっと顔汚くなっちゃったからね、あの準備、して来ようと思います。皆、ちょっと待っててよ。
Ouch, um, my face got a bit dirty, so I'm going to go and get ready. Everyone, wait a moment.
いいもの見せるから。待っててよね、準備してくる！
I'll show you something good. Wait for it, I'll go get ready!
おい、おい、おい、おい、おい、おい、おい。
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
これは！思い出の！
This is! A memory!
通販部屋！
The mail-order room!
ここでね、何億もの商品が、売れたらしいんですね！
I heard that hundreds of millions of products were sold here!
おえ、おえ、おえ、おえ、おえ。
Ugh, ugh, ugh, ugh, ugh.
これは、噂の、ゴリラ部屋！
This is the rumored Gorilla Room!
ついに天国に来ちまったか。
Have I finally come to heaven?
かなたん、おるか？
Kanatan, are you there?
え、天音かなたがやる、桐生ココのモノマネ。
Um, Amane Kanata's impression of Kiryu Coco.
うぅ〜、桐生ココですぅ。
Uhh, I'm Kiryu Coco.
捜査混同すな。
Don't confuse the investigation.
そんなんじゃねぇよバカ！
It's not like that, idiot!
おいおいおいおいおいおいおい！
Hey hey hey hey hey hey hey!
これは！わための！
This is! Watame's!
大草原！爆笑！
Great Meadow! LOL!
わためが、通話してるときに、よくやる適当な返事のモノマネ。
Watame's impression of the random replies she often gives while on a call.
う〜ん。あっ。あ〜。
Hmm. Ah. Oh.
そんなんじゃいないかな？
Isn't it like that?
おいおいおいおいおい！
Hey hey hey hey hey!
おい、おい、おいおいおい、おいおいおい。
Hey, hey, hey hey hey, hey hey hey.
こえ〜よ、なんか。悪魔に悪いことされそう。
Scary... I feel like a devil's going to do something bad to me.
と、常様？常様おる？
T-Towa-sama? Is Towa-sama there?
常様ね、悪魔とか言ってるんですけど、
Towa-sama says she's a devil, but...
何か私の卒業聞いて一番泣いてたの常様なんですよ。乙女なんですよ。
She was the one who cried the most when she heard about my graduation. She's a maiden.
ぴーぴー泣いてんじゃねーぞ！おい！
Don't be crying like a baby! Hey!
んなぁ〜。ここちゃ〜ん。
Nnaaa~ Coco-chan.
あ、う、なななら。行かないで、ほしいなら〜。
Ah, u, nananara. Don't go, if you want~.
ちょっと似てます？ちょっとだけ頑張ったんですけど。
Does it sound like her? I tried a little bit.
ここちゃ、今度、たこ焼き、焼肉、行くなら〜。
Coco-cha, next time, if we go for takoyaki or yakiniku~.
んなは、何もしないのらだけど、見ててな！
Nna won't do anything, but watch me!
んなぁ！おい！
Nnaa! Hey!
おい、おいおいおいおい、おいおいおいおい。
Hey, hey hey hey hey, hey hey hey hey.
ま、やっぱここが一番落ち着きますね。ふぅー。
Well, this place is the most relaxing after all. Phew.
あ、そろそろ時間かな？
Ah, is it almost time?
おいおいおい、では行ってきますね。
Hey hey hey, well, I'm off.
あー、暑い。
Ah, it's hot.
でも寒い。
But it's also cold.
お、なんだか辛そうですね。
Oh? You look like you're having a hard time.
どうしたんですか？
What happened?
ココち、最近一気に暑くなってきて、汗が出てきちゃって。
Coco-chi, it's suddenly gotten hot lately and I'm sweating.
でも、クーラーをつけたら一気に部屋が寒くなるし。
But if I turn on the AC, the room gets cold all at once.
今はちょうど温度の調節が難しい季節な気がしますね。
I feel like it's a season where it's hard to adjust the temperature right now.
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
今は体調管理も大切だから、安易に身体を冷やしてはいけないしね。
Health management is important now, so I can't just cool my body down carelessly.
困ったな。
It's a problem.
この服は暑すぎるし、
This outfit is too hot,
この服じゃ寒いかな。
but this one might be too cold.
なるほど。今の季節にぴったりの服を選ぶのは大変そうですよね。
I see. It seems hard to choose clothes that are perfect for this season.
あー、
Ah,
こんな時に暑さも寒さも気楽に調節できる服があればな。
if only there was an outfit that could easily adjust for both heat and cold at a time like this.
その言葉を待っていたんです！
I've been waiting for those words!
え、まさか...
Eh, no way...
その「まさか」です。
Yes, "no way".
あのあさココブランドがついにアパレル業界に参入。
The Asacoco brand has finally entered the apparel industry.
この季節にぴったりの「あれ」が、ついに発売開始。
That thing that's perfect for this season is finally on sale.
あのCコさんも愛用中。
Even that C-ko-san uses it.
その名も...
Its name is...
「桐生会」代紋ジャージパーカー！！
"Kiryu-kai" Crest Jersey Hoodie!!
やったー、待ってました！
Yay! I've been waiting for this!
このジャージなら着脱簡単。
With this jersey, putting it on and taking it off is easy.
寒いときはしっかり肩まで着用、
Wear it up to your shoulders when it's cold,
暑いときはゆるーく腕まで。
and loosely to your arms when it's hot.
それだけじゃないんです。
That's not all.
激しいバイオレンスな気持ちが抑えられないときは、
When you can't suppress intense, violent feelings,
袖を引きちぎって世紀末スタイルにも。
tear off the sleeves for a post-apocalyptic style.
おー！暑さにも寒さにも世紀末にも対応しているこのジャージ。
Oh! This jersey works for heat, cold, and the post-apocalypse.
使い勝手は圧倒的ですけど、
Its usability is overwhelming, but...
もしかして、結構高い？
is it expensive?
袖引きちぎっちゃったけど。
I tore the sleeves off, though.
そんなことはないんです。
That's not the case.
なんとこちらのジャージ、桐生ココ誕生日記念ということで。
Actually, since this jersey is to commemorate Kiryu Coco's birthday...
10,000円にて販売開始！
It's on sale for 10,000 yen!
い、1万円？
1... 10,000 yen?
紙切れ1枚で買えるなんてお得すぎる。
I can buy it for just one 10,000 yen bill? That's too good a deal.
今すぐ注文しなきゃ。
I have to order it right now!
超お得な代紋ジャージ。
The super-deal "Daimon" Jersey.
ホロライブの代紋も入っていて、超可愛い。
It's got the Hololive "Daimon" on it and it's super cute.
販売期間は短くなっておりますので、
The sales period is short, so
皆様忘れずにご購入を。
everyone, don't forget to purchase yours.
皆さん、見えますか？
Everyone, can you see me?
ここがどこか分かりますか？
Do you know where this is?
このアイドル衣装でステージに立つのは、
Standing on stage in this idol costume is
実は今回がね、初めてなんです！
actually... the first time for me!
アイドル桐生ココお見せできるなんて思ってなかったぜ！
I never thought I'd be able to show you Idol Kiryu Coco!
イエーイ！
Yay!
すごい、あのね、お客さんの前でちょっと緊張しますけど、
Amazing, you know, I'm a bit nervous in front of the audience, but
私もアイドルだったってところを見せたいと思いますね。
I want to show you that I'm an idol too!
それでは聞いてください。
Then, please listen.
桐生ココオリジナルソング、
Kiryu Coco's original song...
My own original song、
My own original song,
Weather Hackers！
Weather Hackers!
負けそうなときは　勇気をあげるよ
When you feel like losing, I'll give you courage
今日も　ハメるあさココで☆
Today too, getting high with Asacoco☆
Weather Hackers☆ 作詞作曲：CielP
Weather Hackers☆ Lyrics/Composition: CielP
お前　どこの組のもんや？
You, which gang are you from?
いい眼をしとるやないけ
You've got good eyes
そんなにボロボロになって
You're so worn out,
どうしたんや？とりあえずまぁ上がれや
what happened? For now, get up
チャカも　ロケランも　格闘もいらないよ
I don't need guns, rocket launchers, or combat
前に進む　勇気があれば
If you have the courage to move forward
君が今踏み出した　力強い一歩で
The powerful step you've taken today
どんな天気も　晴れてゆくよ
Any weather will clear up
どんな天気も 晴れてゆくよ
Even in any weather, it will clear up
（飛ぶぞ〜！ 1, 2, 3, Jump!!）
(Let's fly! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers
朝から ガンギマった
I've been wide awake since morning
みんなのハートに カチコミをかけるんや
I'm going to raid everyone's hearts
Good morning, Weather Hackers
シノギで 疲れはてた
Exhausted from the hustle
みんなのケツから 気合いを叩き込むよ
I'll whip your asses into shape
負けそうなときは 勇気をあげるよ
When you're about to lose, I'll give you courage
今日も ハメるあさココで☆
Getting hooked on Asacoco again today☆
これでもうちは アイドルの
Even so, I'm an idol's
代紋 掲げとるんじゃ
Representing the emblem
全然あやしくないから
It's not suspicious at all
安心して さぁガチ恋になってね
Don't worry, now, fall truly in love with me
合法で安全な あさココグッズキメて
Using legal and safe Asacoco goods
自由な空 羽広げたら
If you spread your wings in the free sky
「飯食ってクソをして寝るだけでえらい！」って
You're great just for eating, pooping, and sleeping!
君の心も 晴れてゆくよ
Your heart will also clear up
（いくよー！ 1, 2, 3, Jump!!）
(Here we go! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers
朝から ガンギマった
I've been wide awake since morning
みんなのハートに カチコミをかけるんや
I'm going to raid everyone's hearts
Good morning, Weather Hackers
シノギで 疲れはてた
Exhausted from the hustle
みんなのケツから 気合いを叩き込むよ
I'll whip your asses into shape
疲れたときには 癒しをあげるよ
When you're tired, I'll give you healing
飛ぼう ヤバいあの草（w）で☆
Let's fly with those crazy "herbs" (w)☆
空に煌めく 雷光
Lightning flashing in the sky
響き渡った 咆哮
A roar that echoed through
未来に輝く 栄光
Glory shining in the future
その夢を 諦めるな
Don't give up on that dream
困難 理不尽も 上等
Challenges and unreasonableness are welcome
まとめて跳ね返す 眼光
With a gaze that bounces them all back
Go your own way!
進め Right now!
Go forward, Right now!
まだ見ぬ 空の向こうへー
To the beyond of the sky yet unseen-
Good morning, Weather Hackers
朝から ガンギマった
I've been wide awake since morning
みんなのハートに カチコミをかけるんや
I'm going to raid everyone's hearts
Good morning, Weather Hackers
シノギで 疲れはてた
Exhausted from the hustle
みんなのケツから 気合いを叩き込むよ
I'll whip your asses into shape
泣きそうなときは 元気をあげるよ
When you're about to cry, I'll give you energy
行こう ゲボかわスマイルで☆
Let's go with a barf-inducingly cute smile☆
皆さん
Everyone,
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
オリジナルソングのWeather Hackersでした！
That was my original song, Weather Hackers!
こちらは実は、全て完全にファンメイドの曲で、
Actually, this is a completely fan-made song,
CLPさんという方が作ってくださいました。
A person named CLP-san made it for me.
ね、あの、自主的に作っていただいたもので、
You know, it was something made voluntarily,
こんなにクオリティが高くて、
and it's such high quality,
実はホロメンも「えっ、あれファンメイドなの？」って
Actually, even the Hololive members were like, "Wait, that's fan-made?"
皆さんにすごくね、驚いてるくらい。
They were all so surprised.
本当に、ありがとうございます！
Truly, thank you very much!
ファンの皆さんが、そんな強い気持ちで
作ってくれた歌でしたから、
Since it's a song the fans made with such strong feelings,
えー、とても気持ちを込めて歌わせていただきました！
I sang it with all my heart!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ではね、もう終わりの時間ということで...
Now then, it's almost time to end...
近付いてきました。
We're nearing the end.
えー、最後に、
Um, lastly,
もう1曲だけ、
just one more song,
例のあれ、歌わせてもらってもいいですか？
may I sing that certain song?
聴いてください。
Please listen.
目を閉じれば億千の星
When I close my eyes, there are billions of stars
一番光るお前がいる
And you are there, shining the brightest
初めて一途になれたよ
For the first time, I could be single-minded
夜空へ響け愛のうた
Echo to the night sky, a love song
純恋歌
Junrenka (Pure Love Song)
作詞作曲：湘南乃風
Lyrics & Composition: Shonan no Kaze
大親友の彼女の連れ　おいしいパスタ作ったお前
Your best friend's girlfriend's companion, you made a delicious pasta
家庭的な女タイプのおれ一目惚れ
I fell in love at first sight with the domestic type of woman
大貧民負けてマジギレ　それ見て笑って楽しねって
Getting seriously mad after losing at Tycoon, looking at that, you said 'It's fun, isn't it?'
優しい笑顔にまた癒されてベタ惚れ
Healed again by your gentle smile, I'm head over heels
嬉しくて嬉しくて柄にもなくスキップして
So happy, so happy, I skipped along, quite unlike myself
朧げな月を見つめる君に釘付け
Transfixed by you gazing at the hazy moon
守りたい女って思った初めて
The first time I thought of a woman I wanted to protect
まじめな顔してギュッと抱きしめた
With a serious face, I held you tight
目を閉じれば億千の星
When I close my eyes, there are billions of stars
一番光るお前がいる
And you are there, shining the brightest
初めて一途になれたよ
For the first time, I could be single-minded
夜空へ響け愛のうた
Echo to the night sky, a love song
これからずっと一緒だお前と俺　最近付き合い悪いと言われるけど
From now on we'll be together, you and I, even though they say I've been neglectful lately
なんだかんだ温かく見守ってくれてる優しい連れな
Somehow or other, you're a kind companion who watches over me warmly
変なあだ名で呼ぶなよ　みんな馬鹿ップルだと思んだろう
Don't call me by a weird nickname, everyone probably thinks we're a stupid couple
でもいつも落ち込んだ時助けてくれるお前の優しい声
But it's always your gentle voice that helps me when I'm down
きっとお似合いな二人　ともに分かり合って重なり合っても
Surely we're a perfect match, even if we understand each other and overlap
折り合いがつかない時は自分勝手怒鳴りまくって
When things don't go well, I yell selfishly
パチンコ屋に込み時間潰して気持ち落ち着かせて
Hiding in a pachinko parlor to kill time and calm down
景品の化粧品持って謝りに行こう
I'll take some prize cosmetics and go apologize
目を閉じれば大好きな星
When I close my eyes, my favorite star
あんなに輝いていたのにな
Even though it was shining like that
今では雲が霞めたまま
Now it's still clouded over
それがなぜかも分からぬまま
Without even knowing why
会いにゆくよ
I'm going to see you
会いに...
To see...
会いに
To see
会いにゆくよ
I'm going to see you
会いに
To see
桜、並木、照らす、朧月
Cherry blossoms, tree-lined road, illuminating, hazy moon
出会ったあの場所へ帰りに寄り道
Taking a detour to that place where we met on the way back
変わらぬ景色変わったのは俺ら二人
The scenery hasn't changed, what's changed is the two of us
見せつけてるつもり目に見えないものなのに
Intending to show off, even though it's something invisible
慣れ合いを求める俺　新鮮さを求めるお前
Me seeking familiarity, you seeking freshness
お前は俺のために　なのにおれはおれのため
You are for me, yet I am for myself
春の夜風に打たれ　思い出に殴られ
Struck by the spring night breeze, beaten by memories
気づかされて気づかされた大事なもの握りしめ
Realizing and having been made to realize, gripping the precious thing
今すぐ会いに行くよ　手を繋いで歩こう
I'm going to see you right now, let's walk hand in hand
絶対離さないその手ヨボヨボになっても
I'll never let go of that hand, even if it gets all wrinkly
白髪の数喧嘩しても
Even if we fight as many times as we have grey hairs
しわの分だけの幸せ
Happiness for every wrinkle we share
二人で感じて生きていこうぜ
Let's feel it together as we live on
LOVE SONG もう一人じゃ生きていけねえよ
Love song, I can't live alone anymore
側に居て当たり前と思ってたんだ
I took it for granted that you'd be by my side
LOVE SONG もう悲しませたりしねえよ
Love song, I won't make you sad ever again
空に向けて俺は誓ったんだ
I swore it to the sky
LOVE SONG 下手くそな歌で愛を
Love song, expressing love with this clumsy song
馬鹿な男が愛を歌おう
This foolish man will sing of love
一生隣で生きていてくれよ
Please stay by my side for the rest of my life
LOVE SONG 何度でも 何度でも
Love song, again and again
LOVE SONG...
何でも話そう
Let's talk about anything
LOVE SONG... 約束しよう
Love song... let's make a promise
目を閉じれば 億千の星
When I close my eyes, a billion stars
一番光るお前がいる
The brightest one is you
初めて一途になれたよ
For the first time, I could be single-minded
夜空へ響け愛の歌
Let the song of love echo through the night sky
目を閉じれば 億千の星
When I close my eyes, a billion stars
一番光るお前が欲しい
I want you, the one who shines the brightest
解き放たれた夜はもう二度と
The nights we were set free will never again...
忘れない届け愛の歌
I won't forget, let the love song reach you
皆さん、今日は来てくれて
Everyone, thank you for coming today
お誕生日をお祝いしてくれて
and for celebrating my birthday with me.
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so very much!
ちゃんと歌えてたかな？
I wonder if I sang okay?
まだお別れじゃないよ
It's not time to say goodbye just yet.
でも、また、今日は本当にありがとう！
But again, thank you so much for today!
誕生日おめでとう自分！
Happy birthday to me!
6/17 HAPPY BIRTHDAY COCO